JOHN HEHER

WEB DEVELOPER

johnheher@gmail.com 1-512-656-9798 johnheher.com linkedin.com/in/johnheher github.com/Heher

Experienced web developer with a focus on the front-end. I have over a decade of dedicated and quality work, ready to help out wherever needed. I'm adaptable to any environment and have worked with big companies and small startups. Most of my career I've been using React with TypeScript/JavaScript but I also have experience using Node and Express for the back-end.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Front-end Developer

Disney+, Remote (Mar 2022 - Nov 2022)

- · Technologies: React, TypeScript, JavaScript, Jest
- Led project for a new onboarding flow for new users, ensuring seamless design across all geographic regions.
- This was a new way for selecting a Disney+ plan when signing up for the service.
- The flow took in multiple APIs across Disney to show/hide content and functionality based on the region's laws and offerings.
- Translated legacy Disney+ code to modern styling and frameworks.
- Consisted mostly of rewriting React class components written in JavaScript to functional React written in TypeScript.

Senior Front-end Developer

Palo Alto Networks, Remote (Mar 2021 - Mar 2022)

- Technologies: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Storybook, Ant Design
- Revamped the dashboard within the company's support portal, enhancing performance and features.
- Legacy dashboard was very slow and hard to update. Helped rewrite components for efficency and readability.
- · Consolidated common styling and components into a new Storybook library.
- Took designs from in-house and wrapped Ant Design components to achieve custom functionality with a consistent look.

Director, Front-end

PHLUR, Austin, TX (Nov 2016 - Feb 2020)

- Technologies: React, JavaScript, GraphQL, Ruby, HTML, CSS, Storybook
- Solely developed and architected all front-end environments in the company, collaborating with designers for pixel-perfect UI/UX and responsive design.
- This included the website, all emails, and any internal tools used within the company.
- Led a comprehensive migration of the codebase to a separate repo using React and GraphQL while adding new products/categories/payment systems.
- Took chaotic mix of jQuery within the existing Rails app when I was hired to a system made from shared React components/styling and streamlined ordering functionality.

Presentation Layer Engineer

Razorfish, Austin, TX (Sep 2014 - Apr 2016)

- · Technologies: Jade, JavaScript, CoffeeScript, Sass, ¡Query, Node
- Helped lead the overhaul of a banking system for Citibank, coordinating with professionals across the globe.
- Worked within multiple teams to create a unified customer portal for Citi that could be whitelabeled with the styling of their partners to feel like a custom experience.
- Took it upon myself to create a unified codebase to align custom styling and functionality with Fortune 500 partners.
- Realizing the dev teams were repeating CSS code, I worked with the lead designer to create a Sass plugin system that could be used to immensely cut down on the developers time styling a partner page.

SKILLS

Front-end Development

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, TypeScript, Email templates

Back-end Development

Node, Ruby on Rails

Testing

Jest, Testing Library, Playwright

Databases

GraphQL, SQL, PostgreSQL

DevOps

Docker, Linode

Accessibility

ADA compliance

Design Tools

Photoshop, Sketch, Figma, Storybook

Lead Front-end Developer

Greenling, Austin, TX (Mar 2013 - Sep 2014)

- Technologies: jQuery, CoffeeScript, JavaScript, Ruby, Sass
- Spearheaded a major rebrand, collaborating with designers to deliver a responsive and efficient user experience.
- Was hired to architect and develop all aspects of the visual and functional redesign of the e-commerce site that also included all changes to marketing and invoice emails.

Senior Web Developer

Traction, San Francisco, CA (Oct 2011 - Jul 2012)

- Technologies: Ruby, YAML, JavaScript, Photoshop
- Coded and QA tested marketing emails for Apple, ensuring consistent display across various devices and browsers.
- Used and developed an in-house Ruby templating system to create emails off Photoshop designs that would be uploaded and sent through Apple's system.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in IT and E-Commerce University of Denver, 2010

PERSONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Slapped by Saint/Pope John Paul II.

Successfully crewed and maintained stern lines in 1,000+ mile journey down the Intracoastal Waterway.

Currently at 64% of goal to visit all Olympic cities and stadiums.

Ongoing multi-decade reign as family Turkey Trot champion.